He's running out of mana!
Don't get your hopes up.
Even if my Archer-class ability to sustain my life reaches its limits,
given the vast difference in our fighting abilities,
it won't even prove to be a handicap.
And, Emiya Shirou...
it doesn't change the fact that you're going to die.
Rin, I will take your heart.
Kotomine, this isn't what we agreed on!
You said you'd give Tohsaka to me!
S-Stop!
You can't have Tohsaka!
Do you have any last words?
I will grant any final request of yours.
You should already know exactly
what's going through my head right now.
True.
Not giving up until the bitter end is your hallmark, Rin.
But what makes you remarkable
is that at the same time you realize
you cannot change what is about to happen.
I admire that.
That contradiction is exquisite.
Lancer... You...
I hate to break it to you, Kotomine,
but I wouldn't be much of a hero if this was enough to kill me.
Damn it all.
So things ended up like this anyway, huh?
Talk about stupid.
"The Holy Grail is yours," my ass!
Once useless, always useless, I suppose.
Isn't that right, holy man?
But I won't make a fuss.
I don't hold a grudge over your actions.
And speaking ill of the dead is unseemly.
Sorry to keep you waiting, Tohsaka!
We've had all kinds of interruptions,
but it's finally just the two of us.
I can't have you going and dying on me that easily.
It wouldn't be fair to me, not after I've been so patient, right?
The Holy Grail is as good as mine!
You still have time, you know.
If you agree to be mine, I might even share it with you.
Good grief.
Have you not learned your lesson?
Don't you get it?
You're the one who still has time, you idiot!
If you don't want to die, get out of here right now!
Grovel for me, Tohsaka!
If I like what I hear, I might just spare your life!
I swear, your stupidity defies all reason.
I'll warn you one last time.
Get out of here right now!
Is that all you have to say?
Who's gonna stop me, huh?!
Stupid kid.
You aren't worthy to touch that woman.
Excuse me?
The dead man walking has a bone to pick?
I'm not gonna let you die painlessly, got it?
Hey, that's your cue, Gilgamesh!
This guy says he wants a hero's death!
Hey.
Come on... What the hell is he doing?
Aren't you listening?
I said to get your ass over here!
Damn it.
Stupid kid made me waste energy.
Thanks. You saved my life.
Well, it just worked out that way.
You don't owe me any thanks.
Lancer!
Crap!
Did you really think your projections were on the same level as mine?
While you may mimic the appearance and material features of the original,
if the structure isn't logically sound, it's worthless.
Damn it!
Now I get it.
That explains why you're so tough.
I've heard of magic that enables you to master old skills
by communing with selves from past lives
and letting them possess you.
It appears that every time our swords clash,
your skills are being honed.
No kidding?
Then I guess we're both copycats.
Keep talking tough.
I'll catch up to you soon enough!
Catch up to me?
You have it completely wrong.
You truly don't understand anything.
What do I have wrong?
Your belief that you ever had the slightest chance of winning!
This is how it all ended for him?
I don't feel sorry for him.
I don't feel sorry for him!
But...
When I think that my feet will be taking me down his path,
my heart feels like it will break.
When I see what you believed in—
what you believe in—
is nothing but a pipe dream wrapped in lies,
I...
Shirou!
Judging by that pathetic expression that says you're about to vomit,
you saw it, didn't you?
That simplifies things, then.
Everything you saw is true, Emiya Shirou.
That's what "catching up to me" will get you.
You should see it once more, with your own eyes.
The world where I ended up.
I am the bone of my sword.
Unknown to Death.
Nor known to Life.
Unlimited Blade Works!
Don't worry about me.
I'm used to this.
Dying because of some dumb order comes with being a hero.
Man, I guess we both got stuck with crappy partners, huh?
You're right.
But I think mine was more "unruly" than "crappy."
That's for sure.
Most humans are a pain in the ass,
but that guy takes the cake.
So he was too much, even for you?
Yes, but that's what motivated me.
As long as Archer was my Servant,
I swore to myself that I'd only do what I thought was right.
I hate to say it, but I can't save him.
Because I think he's right.
His choices, his regret over them...
I think they're all justified.
I'm so dispassionate when it comes to that stuff that I even anger myself.
So all I can do is focus on myself.
Just like a certain someone once did,
I'll keep going down the path I believe in.
That's the only example I can set.
That's about all I could do to repay him.
I'd have no complaints with a woman like you as a partner,
but I never did have any luck at finding good women.
Damn it all.
I guess that'll never change, no matter how many tries I have.
You'd better get going.
I'll take him with me.
Goodbye, Lancer.
I didn't know you long, but I like people like you.
Silly girl.
Come see me again when you have a few more years on you.
The foolishness of appearing here, knowing you're no match for me...
You're a sham who's never had a goal of his own, obsessed with a stupid ideal his entire life.
Is it finally clear that's who you really are?
The need to save people simply because you want to is a faulty emotion.
You're fundamentally broken as a human being—
a fake that should never have existed.
Such a life holds no value at all.
I am your ideal.
It should be clear by now that you're no match for me.
I see.
Your refusal to accept me is only natural.
As long as I am your ideal,
you, Emiya Shirou, must reject me more than anyone.
Then let me ask you.
Do you really want to become a champion of justice?
You're asking me that now?
I don't want to become one.
I will become one!
Yes.
You must become one, no matter what.
And that is because...
it is the only emotion Emiya Shirou possesses.
Even if it isn't something that comes from within himself.
From your reaction, it seems like you have always suspected it.
I no longer remember much of my past.
But nevertheless, I remember that scene.
Flames as far as the eye could see.
The pervasive stench of death.
Wishing for help when all hope was lost.
What I felt when that wish was granted.
The look of relief on Emiya Kiritsugu's face when he saved me.
That is where you began.
Your gratitude for being saved was nothing but an afterthought.
You simply admired Emiya Kiritsugu.
Because he looked so happy when he saved you,
you were convinced that you wanted the same thing.
He's right.
I wasn't the one who was saved that day.
A huge fire without a single survivor.
A child who should have been beyond saving.
A man who found an impossible survivor.
If you were to ask me which was the real miracle, it'd be...
It's only natural for children to idolize their parents.
But what he left you when he died was a curse.
From that moment, you had no choice but to become a champion of justice.
Your ideals are second-hand.
Ideals that Emiya Kiritsugu failed to live up to.
You're just copying what he believed was right.
That's not...
A champion of justice?
Don't make me laugh.
All your talk of wanting to help others
wasn't something you decided yourself.
Someone like you thinking that he could save anyone...
That's the height of hubris!
That's right.
I admired his wish to help others because it was so beautiful!
Consequently, I had no emotions of my own!
If that isn't hypocrisy, what is?
Driven by my obsession with helping others,
I strove toward that goal,
fully aware that it was the height of arrogance!
Shirou!
But in the end, a fake's a fake.
Hypocrisy like that can't save anyone.
No... You won't even know what you ought to save.
Look! This is the result!
Know that an embodiment of cruel justice that never knew how to save—
never had anything to save—
is what you will ultimately become!
Your ideals are bankrupt.
The idea that others are more important than yourself—
the wish for universal happiness—
is just a fanciful fairytale.
If clinging to that dream is the only way you can live,
then let those ideals drag you to your death!
Most of what he said was right.
But I felt like he was forgetting something important.
I saw Hell.
I saw a hell that I would go through someday.
You were... Well...
I guess you were right.
Maybe I could have handled things better.
You seem to have lost many things.
You have it wrong.
I'm here because I was stubbornly intent on losing nothing.
I didn't lose anything.
But...
Yes, there is one thing.
There is one thing that I forgot.
At the very beginning, I saw that hell.
Hey, that's Hell you're walking into.
What was the point of your...
What was the point of my surviving that hell?
Why were we spared?
Hey.
Suddenly
That's Hell you're walking into.
I reached the end of my dream
This is what you forgot.
Where I picked up the pieces of my faded memories
I admit that at first it was just admiration.
But at the heart of it all was a wish.
Love, tenderness
The wish for this hell to be undone.
The unfulfilled wish of a man who only wanted to help others,
I thought I'd thrown it all away
But if I can find what I've lost on the way
but who lost everything in the end.
Then even if I'm destined to be wounded
My heart still harbors hope
Dance, my last stardust
Dust to dust, ash to ash
May my broken wish shine eternal
Even if that life will be that of a machine?
Yeah.
Even if that life is dripping with hypocrisy.
I'll keep striving to be a champion of justice.
Now I see.
Her scabbard.
The link to Saber that Kiritsugu implanted in us to save our life.
That is a sacred relic, not something that was summoned.
Even with the contract severed, it continues to protect him.
I am...
You wouldn't dare...
...the bone of my sword.
Even if I'm destined to be wounded
I can't be...
beaten by you!
My heart still harbors hope
Goodbye, Judas, and turn to dust
Dust to dust, like my past weakness
I don't mind losing to someone else.
But I won't be beaten by myself!
My heart is made of cracked glass
But yet it harbors a long-forgotten warmth
So you've finally got one foot in the door.
But what of it?
Dance, my last stardust
It should be perfectly clear by now
that the difference in our skill is like night and day.
Dance, my last stardust
Dust to dust, ash to ash
My arms and legs still work.
It was my spirit that was beaten.
May my broken wish shine eternal
My spirit was weak for accepting that you were right.
What?
Being right isn't everything.
I don't care about that.
I'll become a champion of justice.
Just as you reject me,
I'll use every ounce of my strength
to defeat the me that is you!
Archer is trying to kill the self that gave rise to him.
You'll lose all hope, just as I have!
My dream isn't a mistake!
Next Time